<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20160302</pubdate>
                <title>National Wild and Scenic River Lines (Feature Layer)</title>
                <geoform>map</geoform>
                <onlink>https://apps.fs.usda.gov/arcx/rest/services/EDW/EDW_WildScenicRiverSegments_01/MapServer/0</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>This polyline feature class depicts the river corridors of each Wild and Scenic River designated by Congress or the Secretary of the Interior for the United States and Puerto Rico. This GIS data layer was created from a mulit-agency effort by the US Forest Service, National Park Service, Bureau of Land Managment, and the US Fish and Wildlife Servce. The spatial data were referenced to the latest High Resolution National Hydrological Data Layer (NHD 1:24,000 Scale or better), published by United States Geological Survey (USGS). Metadata</abstract>
            <purpose>National Wild and Scenic River Lines</purpose>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <sngdate>
                    <caldate>20160302</caldate>
                </sngdate>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>publication date</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>As needed</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-163.299951</westbc>
                <eastbc>-65.748577</eastbc>
                <northbc>69.055061</northbc>
                <southbc>18.233282</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>geospatial</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.

As a work of the United States Government, these data are within the public domain of the United States. Additionally, The U.S. Forest Service waives copyright and related rights in the work worldwide through the CC0 1.0 Universal Public Domain Dedication (which can be found at https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/).</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20250</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>USFS, NPS, BLM, FWS</datacred>
        <native>Esri ArcGIS 10.3.1.4959</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <logic>Quality control measures taken: this feature class is populated by an automated translation process from the source feature class that is edited and maintained by the data stewards. Only stewards with the proper role grants can edit the data. The application used for editing has built in controls to only allow valid geometry and domains to control attribute integrity.</logic>
        <complete>This theme is current to date of publication.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>This data was published using Feature Manipulation Engine Software. The spatial features were extracted from the transactional database, manipulated to meet the desired output format and published to the target feature class. This data was migrated from the CDW. The spatial features were projected and imported into the target feature class.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20160302</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <ptvctcnt>229</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>S_USA.WildScenicRiver_LN</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ORV_SOURCE_DOCUMENT</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the Outstandingly Remarkable Value source document containing the ORV segment information.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Inter-agency Wild and Scenic River Council</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Document Name</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PHOTOCREDIT</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Individual, group or company that provided the photo</attrdef>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>RIVERCATEGORY</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Level at which river is administered</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>Partner WSR</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Partner WSR</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>Partnership and State Administered</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Partnership and State Administered</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>State Administered</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>State Administered</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>Federally Administered</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Federally Administered</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>Tribal Managed</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Tribal Managed</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PUBLIC_LAW_NAME</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The name of the amendatory act(s) designating this river, when meaningful (for example, Omnibus Oregon Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1988 as short title for Public Law 100-557). This field will display “Secretarial Designation” for 2(a)(ii) rivers. Refer to the amendatory legislation available in the Publications portion of the IWSRCC’s website. For multiple names, separate by a comma.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Wild and Scenic Rivers Act and Amendments; www.rivers.gov/act.php</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Document Name</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PHOTOLINK</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>State(s) in which an individual river segment is located.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>State and US Territories.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Length of feature in internal units.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>WEBLINK</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Link to the river specific web page on www.rivers.gov.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>www.rivers.gov</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Web Address</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LOCALWEBSITE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Any local partnership web pages</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Web Address</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>WSR_RIVER_SHORTNAME</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Proper name used for labeling maps and other documentation. "Wild and Scenic River" needs to be added to the end when labeling.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Name</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>RIVER_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique river number that is given at the time of designation. For Congressionally Designated Rivers, per Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act: 1. Use the river numbers designated by Congress. For Secretarially Designated Rivers per Section 2(a)(ii) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (WSRA): 1. Since the Wild and Scenic rivers established under this provision of the WSRA are not assigned a number by Congress, the secretarially designated rivers are assigned a sequence, prefaced by “SD” (Secretarially Designated). 2. For the purpose of assigning sequential numbers, the Wild and Scenic rivers are listed chronologically based on designation date. When more than one WSR was established on the same date, the rivers are listed alphabetically.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Inter-agency Wild and Scenic River Council</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Manually generated numbers</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>WSR_RIVER_NAME</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Official Name of the designated Wild and Scenic River</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Name as designated</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ENACTED_DATE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date the Public Law was enacted.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Wild and Scenic Rivers Act and Amendments; www.rivers.gov/act.php</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>date</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>AGENCY</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Federal government agency that has the primary management responsibility.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Managing Agency</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>NPS</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>National Park Service</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>USFS</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>United States Forest Service (</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>FWS</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Fish and Wildlife Service</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PUBLIC_LAW_NUMBER</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Specific Public Law Number as determined by United States Code.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Wild and Scenic Rivers Act and Amendments; www.rivers.gov/act.php</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>USC (United States Code) number</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>MANAGING_ENTITIES</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Organizations outside of the four federal agencies (NPS, USFS, BLM, and USFWS) who help in managing the river segment. Managing entities can be both government or non-government agencies and/or organizations.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Inter-agency Wild and Scenic River Council</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Managing entity name(s)</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>MANAGEMENT_PLAN</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Availability of river management plan.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Inter-agency Wild and Scenic River Council</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>N</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>No, a river management plan is not available.</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>Y</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Yes, a river management plan is available.</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CLASSIFICATION_SOURCE_DOCUMENT</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the classification source document containing the classification segment information.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Inter-agency Wild and Scenic River Council</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Document Name</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20250</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20170116</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20250</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
